boom okay you try your little sauces I'm
just going to try it plain wow
adventurous as long as I'm trying
something freaky already I just want to
get the full effect the outside is
definitely a little cooked but the the
middle part is raw chicken oh my gosh
okay raw chicken in Japan trying it for
the first time I'm a little scared I'm a
lot scared let's do it here we
go last year with the help of by
food.com I traveled to Tokyo Japan
[Music]
Sushi Ramen Sashimi sake sake
sake is that the right way from food
that can kill you the poison hit my
muscle quickly I can't I
can't to food you have to kill so right
now he's shelling the shrimp the main
thing about the shrimp is that it's
alive right now beautiful ugly and
everything in between wo raw horse I've
never had raw Horsemen this is nuts so
what do you focus on when you feel feel
like you've already covered
everything this time I'm coming back for
round two and we're going deeper in
Japan than any film crew has before on a
mission to hunt down the most unique
food you'll find anywhere in the world
our effort is not fruitless here he's
caught one oh what the
[__] eight videos in eight cities from
Sendai all the way down to Fukuoka
by my side shisuka Anderson TV host in
radio personality raised in Canada but
living in Japan for the last 10 years
welcome to Japan by food I'm your host
shisuka Anderson chizy is a
self-described food lover but this trip
may put that claim to the test now she's
told me to put this on it I'm not sure
what this does oh it bit the spoon
oh in Japan food is more than just food
it's an art worthy of perfecting for a
lifetime a place where the drive for
quality compels shop owners to never
expand beyond their 10- seat ramen
shops where over hundreds of years
meticulous livestock owners bred the
most expensive and best tasting beef in
the
world and where strict adherence to food
and beverage guidelines makes dishes
like raw chicken and raw beef Sashimi
safe to
eat this 8 video series will show you a
side of Japan you have never seen
before our cross country Japan bu food
Journey kicks off in the nation's
capital
Tokyo in this city Ramen is life it is
one of those foods you can find on
almost every street corner Tokyo has
over 10,000 ramen shops and it could
take a lifetime to taste them
all today we're sampling three vastly
different styles of ramen at three
different price tags we have come to our
first noodly location behind us right
now 7-Eleven completely different from
7-Eleven in the USA because here it has
nothing to do with gasoline the one
thing you can't get here here you'll
find everything you need in one place
classic cup noodles with countless
flavors microwavable noodles in a bowl
or fiery noodles in case you're wanting
to ravage your bowels but something even
more special has caught my eye we have
just snuck into a 7-Eleven we have no
permission and this is illegal oh okay
we just got to look just act natural I'm
just so right here they have something
I've never seen before it's kind of
frozen noodles that's right this is your
most standard Japanese style Ramen it is
a soy sauce based Ramen with lots of
chopping it's only 185 Yen wo that's
like $185 okay we're going to make this
actually we're going to ask them to make
this for us cuz the microwaves are all
behind the counter
I did not get kicked out of a s lemon
did you I didn't I walked out
yeah right now our ramen noodles are
soaking up this hot broth what I do love
is that even though it's frozen even
though it's from a 7-Eleven they got a
slice of chachu pork and I'm going to
just get like the best bite of this
whole meal right here let's go for
it m m mhm that's Prett good there are
actually a number of good qualities to
this one is the quality of theod Noles I
would say it's a really good dough it
tastes like a freshly rolled noodle two
point two the soup is also quite good
let's just take a sip of it properly
it's not as like rich and fatty as your
normal broth but not bad the chashi is
kind of hard but I still like the flavor
of it I think for $2 plus the experience
of being in the 7-Eleven interacting
with the local people getting kicked out
people threatening to call the police on
you all that combined into one
experience for absolutely a big bang for
your buck yeah almost a priceless
experience really Priceless yeah we
can't even put a price on this
[Music]
no we've come to our second location an
actual Ramen Shop this is the menu right
here you just walk up here put your
money in and you get a ticket like
you're going on a roller coaster except
the only roller coaster we're going to
go on is a roller coaster of flavor for
our mouths you got that the ramen game
in Tokyo ain't easy the quality price
ing restaurant Ambiance it's all got to
be tops if you want to stick around and
Oreo sh is earning their key this is a
special or which means my way can I add
stuff yes these are the add-on on here
ooh there's cheese guza cheese dumpling
ooh this is a crispy fried chicken with
oh I don't know how to read that oh what
is this it says basil Ramen but in
Japanese it's called jov which is a
pasta basil sauce should we get two
let's do it basil r Ramen or genoves
Ramen perhaps named after the geneves
crime family of New York is a little
Touch of Italy bringing Ramen to the
next level as long as you aren't a
snitch they stir fry a mixture of
veggies including cabbage bok choy
onions carrots and mushrooms add in
chicken and pork bone stock their
Genevie sauce and
pepper drop in those nudes then top it
with chasu pork bamboo choots spinach
green onion a softboiled egg and finely
minced hot
[Music]
chilies this is gorgeous it's like a
work of art this red part looks like
saffron but it's not saffron it is not
it's calledo toari which means thread
red peppers itashi yeah I realized what
we should actually do is try some of
this broth okay cuz this is what makes
it so special it's green it's got basil
let's try it
out wow that's creamy it's not a crazy
intense herbal flavor it's not a punch
to the mouth it's a kiss on the lips
that's a beautiful way to put it I was
with Ramen expert Frank nearly one year
ago he had like Ramen terminology you
know it's a very dramatic pull-up with
the noodles you've got noodle
terminology he calls it a pull he's like
I'll do a deep pull and then an
aggressive
Su yeah
[Music]
M that's a yummy noodle noodles are
still a bit firm I like that they're
very thin I would say a lighter tasting
meal all right Kai check out this suck
get a nice closeup on this is there a
better word for it I don't know a slurp
maybe a slurp yeah I'll stop call
[Music]
that that's good that was an aggressive
slurp so this is just under 10 bucks yes
I'm very curious to see at the next
location how they're going to elevate
something from $9 to $10 all the way up
to $100 maybe like a couple extra meat
slices oh maybe it'll be Rhino
horn that's pretty exotic yeah you can't
even get those in Japan well maybe
today modern day Ramen is versatile for
8 to $10 you can get squid in black as
night darker than my heart this is the
lunch of my dream this chines inspired
Mega Thick broth it's hard to get out cu
broth is almost like fighting against
you to pull it back down they even have
supc Ramen what I thought that was
illegal I didn't think you could do that
now it's legal but how would you elevate
Japanese ramen to its Highest Potential
if price was not an issue the answer
lies here do you know anything about
this place nothing great right now we're
at noodle stand Tokyo it is both ethical
and ramen yes do you know why it's an
ethical I have no idea I actually just
noticed that noodle stand Tokyo just
opened 2 years ago and they already have
a loyal following they use only
ingredients sourced from Japan even
writing the origin of each ingredient on
the menu I checked out the menu already
their most expensive Ramen is only
around $11 today they're making $100
Ramen it's not going to be 10 times the
size they're doing something to it to
make it more expensive what do you hope
is on there I am hoping for truffles
because I love truffles but they're
known to be very expensive oh I'm hoping
for diamonds diamonds that' be that' be
even better earring I came from the
mud desert on my hand Meet The Man
Behind the noodles strong like a tree
are you ready for this a demonstration
of my respect for you making this $100
[Laughter]
Ramen Ramen Master tesi nishimaki he
spent 20 years in the noodle game and
today he's pushing past the limits of
typical Ramen what is your approach for
this luxurious $100
Ramen the main idea is to use Japanese
locally sourced ingredients and also
Japanese wagu that seems like the most
logical step just upgrade the protein a
lot is there any ingredient that you
would never really find in your typical
$10
Ramen today we've decided to throw in a
little bit of [__] to keep it fancy yes
and also truffles you're right I called
it if this is a big hit people come in
here wanting a $100 Ramen will you add
it to your menu yes definitely sir I'm
very excited let's do it first the wagu
steak is seared in oil and garlic then
sprinkled with salt and pepper he adds a
blend of sake and soy sauce and finally
cuts the steak into irresistibly
succulent
slices next up Sukiyaki thin beef slices
dipped in a mixture of soyu sauce sugar
and seaweed now it's time to bring it
all together our giant bowl that we're
definitely sharing cuz I can't afford to
is filled with a soy sauce base oyster
sauce and a dreamy milky
broth the noodles are delicately placed
in the center stacked with slices of
beautiful rare
wagu now the Sukiyaki white asparagus
naganegi half a seasoned egg a d of
truffle oil on the beef Bonito or dried
fish Flakes and finally as a pure symbol
of over-the-top opulence pure gold
[Music]
flakes here we are I've never been
so excited to eat something as I am
right now neither have I I think this is
a collection of all the finest
ingredients in Japan the best Bonito
flakes the best gold this is a very
special brand of egg called oku kjaa
which is Apparently one of the higher
quality eggs in Japan it's a good egg
we've got this beautiful wagu on each
side two different cuts I we can get
just a piece of this because it's one
it's got gold two it's got truffle sauce
three it's wagio and that's enough
[Music]
oh my
God that was outstanding W that's one of
the best bites of my life truffle can
usually be too much or too little and
that was perfect the wagu just melts in
your mouth very tender it's got some
broth still clinging to it so it's Rich
Savory that was amazing that was a taste
of Heaven this here is the sirloin have
you ever felt so fancy eating wagyu beef
like covered in gold
God
damn that is remarkably tender it
actually melts in your mouth it's very
rich and very fatty take a look guys
this might be the best bite of ramen
that exists anywhere we've got wagu A5
some Bonito some noodles some
broth oh that is so good the combination
of everything just explodes in your
mouth that broth has like a deep
savoriness to it you can get that umami
in there yeah altogether it's incredibly
Rich here they have something I've never
seen combined with Ramen kind of a
fagra paste yeah they said we can
actually just kind of mix it into the
broth and then even put a little extra
on a bite so I want to try
that it changes everything it's just
like a more fatty Rich note at the end
of the eating
cycle you guys buying this I think the
eating cycle is a little bit later the
end
we came to the nice folks here at noodle
stand and we asked them hey can you make
an outstanding top-of-the-line luxurious
opulent Ramen and honestly they
delivered hardcore it looks amazing it
tastes even better and I couldn't be
more satisfied I agree like this is
meant for one person we shared it but I
would say good bang for your buck good
bang for my buck that's for share not my
buck
our Japanese CrossCountry food tour has
officially begun moving from Tokyo to
the city of
Sendai Cai is known for Sendai which is
Sendai wag Sendai is the largest city in
the tahu region a city popular for
delices that you can't find just
anywhere
oh look at that egg yolk today is all
about the famous Japanese tradition of
eating meat raw honestly it's not really
my thing that I want to be eating but
I'm going to do it I don't know how it's
anybody's thing today we're taking raw
meats to the extreme this isn't a normal
food to eat concluding with the most
dangerous food I have ever eaten raw
chicken I am shocked that this food even
exists welcome to coutur a restaurant
specializing in raw beef dishes
including their own raw beef on
Rice we are in the kitchen with Mr dice
K Shi sir thank you so much for having
us today sorry double handshake
handshake Ultra respect how long have
people been eating raw beef in Japan
historically speaking in Japan we
haven't been eating raw meat just
because it is dangerous
great eating raw beef can be highly
risky since it may contain bacteria like
eoli or salm Manilla and both could
prove fatal is it worth the
risk yes yes that's 100% confident that
was a big yes what is so special about
Robbie oh you don't even need a like
that I felt that in my
heart I love this guy's passion for beef
yes I saw this laying around can you
tell me about this one this is actually
just beef sushi sushi doesn't mean raw
fish it means sour rice and it's the
same rice used to make raw beef niri an
oblong hand pressed mound of rice and a
thin slice of raw beef covered with a
bit of Wasabi and finally brushed with
soy sauce please shair in this moment
with me here's mine o
cheers m
M oi M that is so good surprisingly has
a lot of layers for being so simple the
little bit of Wasabi and then just the
salt on top with the soy sauce wow that
was a great appetizer thank you so
[Applause]
[Music]
much today we came especially for the UK
a Japanese dish similar to beef Tartar
and coutur was the first restaurant in
Japan to serve
it to prepare the raw beef safely the
restaurant first blanches a large cut of
top round at a high temperature to kill
any existing bacteria on the meat
surface then they cut away the cooked
section leaving only pristine and
bacteria-free raw beef that is perfectly
safe to
eat from here they mince the beef By
Night adding an in-house sauce sesame
oil and a mixture of vinegar and miso
plate it top it with an egg yolk and
garnish with cucumber green onions
sesame seeds and a
flour here we are we have this tiny cute
adorable creation for about $15 right
yeah but before we eat it did you know
that someone has actually died eating
this before really actually five people
have died eating this this seems like
folklore it actually happened in 2011 it
was huge news all over Japan and because
of that we forced lots of restaurants to
stop serving it why are you so happy as
you tell this story no not one person
five of them died isn't that great let's
do uh less thinking and more
chewing oh look at that egg yolk nice
break that is so gorgeous this is one of
the gooiest foods I've ever tried here
we
go wow wo that's worth dying
for it really is it really is the egg
goes so well with this it's very creamy
melty soft and the texture you know it's
not just straight minced it's like half
chopped half minced there's still a
lovely texture in your mouth too from
here when will we find out if we might
die good question you I'm not sure it
won be during this
video our next stop nanu isaka a
Japanese pub run by Miss Enda kanako
since its Inception 7 years ago the
afterwork crowd can't get enough of her
odang Japanese fish cakes and our next
raw food delicacy shark
heart we are here right now with Miss
kako thank you so much for having us I'm
told you have raw shark heart is this
true hold this yes it's true he says yes
with pride how many people are eating
this shark heart about half of all the
customers will order these shark Hearts
to some in Japan shark meat has a long
list of health benefits not the least of
which includes skyrocketing male libido
but I'm sure it's good for other stuff
too I love your restaurant I love the
feel in here I can see that you have a
heart and I can't wait to see you put
your heart into making the shark
[Music]
heart shark meat especially the Oregon
have an intense ammonia Aroma that needs
to be flushed out over a couple hours
can I smell it the meat itself is cut
into thin slices and the arteries are
chopped even more finely Boom the raw
shark heart what I like is that it's not
just heart it's heart and valves why
don't you grab
something sorry I didn't even mean to
say that that's all right just go from
the heart one 2
3 oh you actually did it huh oh I'm not
going to eat that
I'm just kidding here we
go the texture is very it's like a firm
sponginess the flavor is not strong at
all when you mix it with the sesame oil
it's just kind of a rich Smoky salty
flavor but here we have valve and that's
got to be easier
right you were doing great at the beef
part what happened I'm not an organ
girl must be a lonely
life let's try it out here we go
the texture is completely different
chewy in Japanese we say Cody Cody oh
it's so Cody Cody the only thing I can
compare it to is a penis fish it's like
eating tendons I like it I like the
texture it's a little funky and all you
need on the side is like a couple liters
of sake to really bring it home yep
that'll do
it our last stop today knee Diamond
since 2008 they have been serving a
specialty that if prepared in
incorrectly can actually kill you I'm
talking about raw chicken how many
people in Japan have died from eating
raw chicken I actually haven't heard of
anyone dying at least it hasn't become
you know wild news or the raw chicken
Mafia just sweeps it under the rug
they're serving it behind us let's go
inside and figure out how this
[Music]
works Mr K cardino thank you so much for
having us today are you terrified are
you excited there's literally millions
of people watching right now this is doy
doie it's an automat toia for your heart
pumping oh okay here you have a couple
special things on the menu first of all
horse
[Applause]
meat horse meat is a popular dish from
kushu in southern Japan and it's
actually more common than you'd think
eaten in Mexico Switzerland Indonesia I
even tried some in usbekistan
but Japan is the only place I've seen
serve it raw and what separates hor meat
from any other animal like beef
or beef horse meat is completely
different from eating raw beef you can
enjoy this and not be afraid of
dying that's something I really look for
when I eat food it's like ah not
dying Mr K tried his first Bashi when he
traveled to kushu it was love at first
bite and he's been serving fresh horse
Bashi ever
sense he cuts the meat into paper thin
slices served simply with a side of
garlic miso paste and
[Music]
scallions let's go for it
Go m m I love that ooh that is really
good a little more firm mhm oh and then
it has some interesting aftertaste it's
a bit horsey what's the taste of horse
it's hard to explain I mean it's heavy
it's robust you got to try horse unless
you like horses a lot but then you can
still try it anyways and just don't tell
the horse that who is your
friend our final dish raw chicken if any
food kills me on this show it will be
this one I mean I'm actually scared this
time the Japan tour hasn't even started
and it could be over already I am
shocked that this food even exists I've
been all over the world eating crazy
stuff and honestly nothing scares me
more than what we're about to try right
now have you ever heard of someone
getting sick from eating raw
chicken the names of all the people who
have died no no no Len all the names
this is a really common dish sir my life
is in your hands and my bowels also in
your hands let's do this height do what
height the raw chicken achieves safe
eating status using the same preparation
method as the raw beef the outside
chicken breast is briefly blanched
killing any bacteria or cell Manilla
what remains is the raw bacteria-free
inside the chicken Sashimi is sliced
thin and spread on a plate like an
alluring raw chicken
flour raw chicken Sashimi I am doie DOI
doy doie doy DOI doie doie all right
let's do this I'm just going to try it
plain wow adventurous I just want to get
the full effect it looks like it was
cooked rare let's do it let's do
it wo that is actually surprisingly very
good I love like it like I am very
pleasantly surprised I was ready for
like a raw chicken type of texture but
no it's it's kind of melt your mouth it
did anything but melt in my mouth it was
stubborn okay I'm going to try it with
some
sauce it's literally like eating sushi I
can definitely tell I'm eating raw
chicken it doesn't take me to like a
different world or anything I'm so
confused like all the flavors are there
but my brain is so conditioned to not
eat raw chicken that it's like mistake
mistake mistake with every bite like
hearing his explanation seeing his
preparation and knowing that he thinks
that he probably hasn't killed anybody
that was enough for me to feel pretty
secure our CrossCountry Japan food tour
continues as we move from Sendai to
Fukushima I came here to see if life has
returned back to normal after the tragic
tsunami and nuclear disaster that
occurred 8 years ago there was a huge
huge earthquake which caused the tsunami
to come and then the tsunami affected
the nuclear reactor how did Japan
recover from that let's
go while we're at it we're stepping back
into Japanese Traditions that have
withstood the test of time if you trust
me I want to see how tight of a pattern
we can get 3 2 1 including unique Foods
you wouldn't expect to see in Japan oh
can I eat it if I don't look get it yeah
I could drop it in your
mouth ending with the fish you do know
from Japan but never expected to see on
a dinner plate before we get into the
cooking I do want to ask more seriously
like what is koi in
Japanese come along as we car the load
to every Ro in country code
[Music]
say let's get
started as we set foot in Fukushima
prefecture everything seems normal quiet
Countryside Ambiance the smell of
vegetation but deep inside these fields
lies a unique creature that'll become
part of an almost unheard of Japanese
dish here we are we are in a field in
where where are we again katashi
Fukushima I'm told we're going to catch
grasshoppers today yeah you seem like a
pro cuz you're wearing gloves I mean
look how I'm dressed obviously I'm not
ready I didn't know so this is masamichi
igawa he knows everything about
Countryside living including what to do
with these
grasshoppers people in Japan used to eat
them more commonly a long time ago but
the tradition still continues today I
came here about a year ago I posted a
lot of videos about Japan Japanese food
and there's comments here and there
about people being freaked out about
radiation in food because of what
happened here how did Japan
recover we had tons of volunteers who
came out and actually helped clean up
rebuild was a huge effort it took
years he says that now there's actually
no danger anymore they actually eat the
local vegetables like raw they actually
do screenings and tests for the rice so
it has become safe at this point
although the food coming from this
region has been thoroughly checked and
vetted there's still a lot of work to be
done in winning back the trust of other
regions and other parts of the world
what I know for sure is these
grasshoppers are good to go chy I like
you're pushing yourself to do new things
I try my
[Laughter]
best catching grasshoppers is pretty
easy right now we're literally walking
past thousands of them spot your prey oh
sh there's big ones here move swiftly
here we go one two oh
no but above all else there's one
literally right here it's a gift from
God you must
commit
yes amazing
thank you do you think I'm brave a
little
bit I've tried delicious food from all
over the world [__] food that other
people cook why are they gone but
there's nothing like the sense of
satisfaction that comes from getting out
there no no come
in and catching your own meal I'll try
another
one I'm trying
there's a grasshopper on this Leaf it
almost wants to be caught it looks a
little sad it looks a little depressed
it's kind of over this whole living
thing what it wants is to be caught and
join his friends in the bottle but what
it needs is for you to take some action
swoop it up like the hand of
God yes it's in my hand yes it's moving
you're out of my hand I don't like it
you did it there it is look you got a
huge one
don't you feel that Adrenaline Rush
don't you feel amazing like you
accomplish something I am a
hunter
yeah
yeah we've got today's secret ingredient
Mami brings us to a local home where all
the cooking action is about to go down
including Japan's riskiest food making
procedure
[Music]
as far as I understand there's two
people with hammers and then there's one
unlucky person who has to stick their
hand in there and that's uh our friend
right here how you doing too
scared you should be joining our lunch
today Mochi a sticky gooey classic
symbolizing Japan's Timeless ability to
innovate with everything around them it
starts by soaking rice in water
overnight the next day it's strained
through a cheesecloth and steamed for 1
hour before it's pounded in a wooden
mortar man if you trust me I want to see
how tight of a pattern we can
[Music]
get Yeti me here we go three 2
hey this is the product right here it's
crazy sticky it won't even come off his
hands oh my goodness this is more than I
can chew let's try it out
oh it's so weird it's like the unrefined
version it's so sticky and clumpy pure
Mochi freshly pounded rice cake with no
flavoring at it are you going to eat
this part on your
arm Mochi is a Carby amorphous base and
there's so much you can do with it add
vegetable broth to make emoi soup top it
with red bean paste coat it in soybean
flour creating a yellow V vibrant
dessert and if you want something more
wild top it with Nat Japan's Infamous
sticky fermented
soybean hi what's your name my name is
oh you speak English no okay I can't
speak English joining our meal Mr yiro
and his wife Asami I think we should
jump into it so shizuka oh no have you
ever had a bug never this is what we
came here for the grasshopper is boiled
in hot water to remove any dirt then
it's stir fried in a blend of sugar soy
sauce and sake a blend that creates
homemade teriyaki sauce I want you to
grab a few should I help you I can diss
you up some let me just look at this
don't look at them that's the last thing
you should do is look at them the chest
the chest she got one okay we'll do it
together listen look at this I got two
right here let's do this oh can I eat it
if I don't look at it yeah I could drop
it in your mouth oh God is that what you
want all right I'm going to try it out
right I'm going to try it hold on
try oh that's really good was sweet and
salty it's like Teriyaki grasshoppers
Teryaki
[Music]
grasshoppers yeah it's just crunchy
papery there's no gooiness it's a pretty
good sell it's not bad it's not not bad
mhm mhm right here this is watchi with
natto natto natto
mhm oh do people he does it just smell
good it's a pretty normal smell for them
it doesn't smell bad but to me it's
obviously fermented oh yes it's stringy
it's so unique oh he just mixes it up
like that mix it up the more you mix it
the healthier it
[Music]
gets wo that's a chewy mouthful yeah I
took too much could know open your mouth
for a second the smell is more intense
than the flavor the flavor itself is a
bit more mild definitely slimy it's like
slime on slime crime over here it's all
just a texture sensation I'm actually
really liking this foreign people think
it's such a strange food but in Japan
they'll eat it like every morning right
here it's our dessert let's try it
out
M that's some good stuff same sticky
texture a little bit sweet and then a
little
bit what do you call that like
nutty earthy nutty might be the best way
to describe it to me this seems like
traditional Japanese dessert it's not
like a cake with frosting it's just got
some subtle sweetness to
it talking about the event 8 years ago
what kind of impact did that have on
your lives here if
any he was actually working in Tokyo at
a company and then after the earthquake
and the disaster happened that made him
want to come back home and support his
hometown that's incredible like yiro and
his wife many many others return to
Fukushima helping to rebuild it into
what it is
[Music]
today before leaving Fukushima I've got
a unique opportunity to try out a rare
freshwater fish native to this part of
Japan a species you may know as koi
fish
sir thank you
[Music]
this place is the perfect Retreat from
the city restaurant hotel and hot spring
in one open 146 years ago and
specializing in traditional foods that
reflect Japanese culinary history on
your large menu you've got one dish that
stood out to me but before we get into
that I want to ask what is koi in
Japanese koi is a c fish it's about this
big and they get it from local rivers in
ISU this fish is most famous its bright
vibrant colors in Japan koifish
symbolize persistence determination
wealth success and good fortune I've
seen them in picturesque ponds but never
on a dinner
[Music]
table can I tell you something funny I
came here cuz I thought we're going to
eat one of those like koi goldfish it's
going to be like colorful and white and
orange and then people are going to be
like no don't do it I'm going be like
I'm doing it anyways um but I don't
think it's that kind of fish what kind
of koof fish do you have
here you may have thought that you would
be eating those beautiful colorful koi
fish that are usually found in Japanese
Gardens and ponds but actually those are
not fish that are meant for eating and
we have separate breed of koi fish that
are actually designed for eatings are
they still
cute kawaii kawaii when you grab one can
you try to find like just the cutest one
of the ones that you have okay okay okay
thank you thank you
[Music]
these fish well they'll meet the
business end of a filet knife and join
their friends in a dish called koi umani
big pieces of fish simmered with soy
sauce sugar and homemade sake for 9
hours when the fish becomes tender and
the broth becomes thick it's ready to be
served
[Music]
everyone quiet I'm in
character hey guys welcome back to the
food show so right here this is a
koifish this is also a koifish tada
T we're in like this restaurant Suite a
private room which has a little bit of
everything beautiful background over
here is that a hot plate there's a tea
station over here they have have a a 7in
TV can you explain this place to me I
kind of don't get it this is a room you
can sleep in so you eat here and then
you put your futons out then you sleep
sleep or pass
out probably both cuz I
mean oh that's nice wow that's smooth M
and here it is a nice kind of
caramelized glaze on the outside it
would seem and I think I'm going to
start in the middle you think that's egg
I have no idea maybe it's grasshopper no
it better not be it better not be any
but grasshopper all right let's try it
out Cheers Cheers
[Music]
Cheers that's egg it's kind of like
crumbly on the inside but it's all kind
of held together with this thick soy
based glaze a little sweet a little
salty mhm it tasted like an actual
chicken egg like the yolk that's been
cooked let's bust into this meat right
here it comes out real nice I don't
think carp have scales they do I'm
quitting my sh
M ooh that's very nice I would say oi
it's so soft it's become tenderise from
all the boiling but a powerful flavor M
I never expected that carp was going to
be this good it doesn't have any strange
aftertaste and very tender it's
delicious it happened again
Fukushima a region acutely plagued With
Disaster after disaster is now a symbol
of Japanese resilience and persistence a
feat only made possible through the
incredible fighting Spirit of the
Japanese
[Music]
[Applause]
people welcome back to our Japan series
we are a long way from Tokyo and we've
got a surprise for you that you won't
find in any of our competitors channels
I'll tell you that definitely
[Music]
not this is
enoshima poost of the 20120 Summer
Olympic sailing competition and famous
for its enoshima
Shrine but if you know our show you know
that's not why we're
here from this to this how did that
happen this unique Island also boasts
some of the most unusual food you'll
find in Japan okay God and one local
Secret ingred inent seems to find its
way into almost every
[Music]
dish it's so creepy it looks like a
fossil today shizzy and I are hitting
the docks hello sir to sneaking our
cameras into the fish factories what am
I eating and sweet talking our way into
the kitchen I don't like gross little
things all to attempt to get some
answers to the question with gold what
happened to the island of enoshima
[Music]
right now we're at the dock Pier what do
you call this boat area the piece of
concrete that has many boats on
it in the southern part of kakura City
along the coast sits Koshi go fishing
report one of the biggest shirasu
suppliers in the area right now we are
awaiting the arrival of a local
fisherman who has a shirasu Blog yes he
does every day he's updating how many
shirasu he caught shirasu in English is
called White bait they're little tiny
white fish we're eating the bait that's
right white bait it's a term for
immature fishes that are so small their
only purpose is to swim around and get
eaten by bigger cooler
fish white baits are tender and edible
in Japan these baby sardines are a
delicacy our ship has arrived hello sir
hello K very excited back from sea you
can see the enthusiasm in their eyes oh
and they're going past us it looks like
they had an amazing catch all these huge
coolers completely full of shirasu this
is much more than I expected
yeah
oh
oi these baby sardines are called
shirasu processed shirasu appear in many
Japanese Delicacies especially across
the bay on the island of enoshima you
guys need
help nice help how deal it's used in
snacks as a topping main ingredient or
this today's shirasu catch is
transported immediately in these coolers
to keep them fresh from here they take a
short ride to a nearby Factory for
processing the processing of the shirasu
is underway but are some people eating
this raw they do actually enoshima is
one of the places to you can eat them
raw normally you would eat them over a
bowl of rice oh you don't think it's
normal just to hold 20 lbs of fish in
your hand and eat it raw no no
okay oh come on you didn't do grass
offer you have to do
this can I eat it if I don't look at
it yeah I could drop it in your mouth oh
God I don't like gross little things
okay holding it I'm holding it let's try
it out the Raw shirasu
okay like it's a little crunchy a little
salty and a little like an tropies but
it doesn't have any super strong flavor
no it doesn't it's not bad oh you're
holding it together pretty well now I
did it I'm on some s you cannot touch me
it's for the best you just Lear to me
the fish are gathered and washed huge
baskets are boiled for 5 minutes too
long and the fish fall apart do you know
why they choose to process it in this
way is it to preserve it they usually
ship it all across Tokyo so in order to
do that they usually need to be boiled
after boiling the fish are placed on a
dry net spread out evenly and left Under
the Sun for 30
minutes oh hey thank you that's that's a
lot no that's the exact portion I wanted
that's
[Music]
good okay they've become sticky it helps
it helps let's go for it here you go oh
W better much better they're not as
slimy anymore not as slimy and not as
much like Oceanic flavor it tastes good
from here they're going to package it up
many of these go to Tokyo but a lot of
them end up at sard Island which is
where we're going next that's not what
it's actually called that's what I've
called it welcome to enoshima Island I
call it shirasu heaven and I came ready
to
[Music]
eat Asahi hunen is the only place on the
island that sells shirasu crackers with
their exclusive recipe made by Mr
mitsuru Sir yeah hi hello hello they've
been operating for 16 years hugely
popular for those who want to see how an
entire octopus can become a cracker in
seconds it's seriously mindboggling
stuff it doesn't seem feasible right now
he's working on it he's putting some oil
on this super hot flat top so he's got
octopus and he's dipped it in potato
starch that's it this is my favorite
part so he closes
it
[Applause]
[Music]
he are they dying about three octopus
scream open open open already and would
you look at that three separate
octopuses turned into one cracker how is
that even legal right got
paper all right let's go for IT smash
papery
octopus yummy yummy a little salty
seafoody but the texture is what I'm
more amazed by it's legit cracker I
thought there would be some parts that
were inconsistent some parts chewy some
parts soft and it looks kind of
beautiful at the same time I heard they
have two more kinds here they make one
with shrimp and they make one with chasu
that's why we're here we're going to try
those
next with almost the same technique and
ingredients they take a shrimp sit it on
a bed of batter press it for 1 minute
and it's done it was kind of normal
sized and then they just crushed it they
flat and it's literally like paper thin
that's amazing the shirasu cooks up a
little differently first it's blue like
the ocean and the fish are multicolored
also like the ocean press it in the
cracker maker 3000 and bazook
a child's kindergarten art is revealed
and you can eat it
too ooh that's pretty good it's fishy
and the texture is super unique tastes
like you're eating styrofoam oh yeah
it's like a little bit of a foamy fish
cracker still looks
crispy
oh it's a little thicker a little
tougher there do you want a head or a
butt of the butt oh that one's a little
more crispy yeah don't break your teeth
this is like where the life force of the
shrimp ended was right here you're right
but it gives it a really strong shrimpy
taste yeah that is MHM shrimpy shrimpy
[Music]
H and oima is just a day trip from Tokyo
these days it's packed and the shirasu
boom can be thanked for luring in
Curious tourists
hello according to the manager this
restaurant started the shirasu trend
over a decade ago here at toic Cho the
shirasu even makes its way into your
booze well interestingly enough this
shop actually may have been the start of
sh's ice cream as well my main question
is why is there fish in the ice cream
can you explain that real quick today's
menu S shuru no shirasu d a rice bowl
with three different types of
shirasu it starts innocent enough with a
bowl of rice add some veggies mayonnaise
sesame seeds and dry seaweed then boiled
sardines soy sauce sardines and raw
sardines it's finally topped with minced
yellow Ginger minced radish and minced
spicy radish along with our main dish
shirasu Maki Sushi and shirasu croquet
it is shirasu heaven in here it is if
you were a fish that eats Bait fish you
would love this restaurant or if it were
a bird or something I think we should
work our way around the table first of
all this seems like an appetizer if I've
ever seen one I want to go for half of
it here we go
it's good I like it there food it
wouldn't be my usual choice for this
style of sushi but man that is it's full
of fish oh here's sake so before you
came in here I put the sake a dried fish
chip W with gold you're right there's
little gold flakes in it it's opulent
she
is
M next I want to bust this open and I'm
hoping a bunch of fish come swimming out
bamboo charcoal where are the fish man I
came here for the fish oh there they are
they've been kind of minced and mashed a
bit M I like that no gustatory evidence
of
fish I love
it what we have here is the classic siru
rice bowl with three different types
of shirasu on the side they have a
cooked egg or a raw egg we can use
either one add a little bit of soy sauce
to it you got to mix the yolk first with
the soy sauce and then pour it over ooh
oh wow it's so thick and YY did you go
to the same food reviewing school as me
I want to try this one cuz this the only
kind of shirasu I've been tried 80 times
today it's one in soy sauce it's raw
it's also it is raw also
yeah M okay that's really nice I feel
like I've come a long way from the
beginning of this video okay holding it
I'm holding I never thought I would be
able to eat rasu honestly cuz the
appearance of foods takes me out of it
quite a bit but I mean once you can get
past that anything you set your mind to
you can add fish too do you want to have
a good tonight I want to have a good
time tonight you know we're going to
have a good time tonight I said we're
going to have a good time tonight let's
go shasu
shirasu believe it or not this is the
only shirasu burger shop on this island
Shan Burger first they toast the buns
then the shirasu cake is fried and
dipped in a bowl of soy sauce add some
Wasabi lettuce shirasu cake a pile of
boiled shirasu and lube it up with some
mayoo here's step one for me I'm going
to put his little hat on put the Hat on
my favorite part is I thought they'd put
like 10 fish but look how many [__]
fish are in there
[Music]
I like that a lot I don't even taste
them you wouldn't know that there was a
shasu fish in here unless someone told
you I kind of feel them like they're
small and Meaty but that's kind of it
nice dense fish Patty in there just a
pile of shirasu this is one shirasu dish
that I think I could actually get on
board
with okay o
[Music]
o shirasu they make may be tiny but
these little fish have had a huge impact
on Japan's most unique food
[Music]
Island our cross country Japanese food
tour continues moving from Kanagawa to
shizuoka you got to be a psycho to eat
this in search of a food so strange most
local people have never even heard of
it this is an ISO hot a creature living
on the ocean floor hundreds of meters
below the surface this is a creature
created by Satan himself a creature man
was never meant to see let alone eat I
don't know this should be illegal right
we're hitting the high seas so exciting
waiting through the rolling waves look
W and hoping for a lucky or not so lucky
catch I'm stuck in an ocean nightmare it
won't
[Music]
end well welcome to shizuoka home of the
famous Fuji
Mountain but we came here for something
much more special sir thank you so much
for having us here this morning we're
about to jump aboard your ship do you
have a cute name for your boat it's
called CH what does that mean it's a
boat name okay how long have you been a
man of the sea since he was 16 and he is
now 70 I thought you going to say he's
down 17 so for one year Mr hasagawa has
been working on a boat his whole life he
started as a deep sea shark fisherman
and later transitioned to isopods now he
and his son provide deep sea tours to
adventurous isopod craving Travelers
like me but how did they come up with
this isopod business idea one day he
started getting them for aquariums and
he tried cooking them in this steam pipe
over here and it turned out that it was
really delicious then TV crew came and
that's kind of how the popularity spread
and now you can even get rice crackers
made with isopods by the way you're 70
why do you have more hair than me it's
because he's drinking extract of the
sharks that he
catches and his hands are beautiful are
there other benefits men his wife gets
tired of him because he's so energetic
energetic yes if we fail with the
isopods I'm getting some shark
[Music]
extract if I was going to be a winner
then I'm grow up be get leaving the
docks Fresh Ocean Air in my face feeling
hopeful only 1 hour on the high seas
Separates Me from the goal also shizzy
is definitely excited come on if I was
going to be a winner then I'mma grow up
to be a
gold oh no everything was fine a second
ago now we're in the actual ocean I'm in
the worst spot on the boat I don't know
if you guys can see how crazy
these
pleas considering Japan is one of the
most strict rule following countries in
the world I am now shocked that Mr
hasagawa didn't even give us a short
safety brief warning us about this 10 m
long death trap he calls a
boat seasickness is inevitable morale is
going from good down to why the hell did
Sunny bring us
here this is by far the shakiest boat I
have ever been on I don't know how we're
going to actually survive being on the
boat I'm so fre that I been on the boat
but it's all for a good purpose it's to
show you guys one of the creepiest
craziest strangest Foods they have in
Japan it's called an isopod they're
known as the janitors of the
sea carnivorous Crustaceans munching on
all the dead sea animals that fall to
the ocean floor they're part of the
circle of life essential to Ocean
ecosystems if you were wondering what
happened to your dead goldfish you flush
down the toilet when you were five these
guys probably ate it
[Music]
we've come here to their buoy we've
dropped anchor it's a little bit less
Rocky now but still not that great
everyone's feeling pretty sick how are
you feeling right now I'm trying to fend
off the motion sickness o y how deep is
it 400 m deep right here I can see land
400 m away that is crazy deep below us
lie their isopod traps long black
cylinders filled with
bait the isopods can crawl in but they
can't crawl out right now the Trap line
is slowly being lifted we don't know
when it's going to come up it's going
like a meter a second while we wait let
me share some tips on how to shoot a
show on the water tip one make it fun
this is like the fourth level of fun tip
two cast a fearless and articulate host
are there cages down there they've got a
big cage they had a buoy to Mark where
the cage is as soon as they bring this
cage up it's going to be a big cage any
minute this cage is going to come up
here and maybe we got a Bonus cage tip
three research you should know exactly
what to expect here it is so it's not
even a cage it's a cylinder oh what the
[__] what are those
creatures oh no it's got little isopod
it's like a cross between a cockroach
Lobster and a nightmare these isopods
look strong active and ready for eating
first they must be dispatched sliced
down the front expelling a toxic putrid
ball of oceanic waste from their gut
it's the worst thing I've ever smelled
the camera guy can confirm that are you
going to throw up oh
no was that the isopod or the ocean
sness I don't know guys can we keep
going I don't know if we can keep
[Applause]
going this isn't really what I had
planned today was supposed to be a fun
food Adventure on the high seas instead
morale is
low but it's not always about fun we're
on a mission to dig up Japan's most
bizarre food and now we have enough
isopods for a
lifetime the seas are a bit choppy the
crew's taken a hit we had a little bit
of a spew problem here and there I
mean we did accomplish our mission we
got the seab bugs I don't think you're
going to find this anywhere else in the
world if these creatures weren't strange
enough wait until you see how the
captain Cooks them the gutted isopods
are tossed in a wire cage and the cage
is set in the boat's exhaust
pipe roasting or rather scorching these
creepy crawlers in fumes that can reach
over 2,000 de before we Chow Down we're
heading back to the dock so the team can
get a much needed escape from the
ocean's NeverEnding onslaught of choppy
[Music]
waves guys we have just got back to land
oh sweet land look at it it's right
there oh I love that land so now that
we're not rocking so much I can get a
closer look this is the isopod it's got
this little tail kind of similar to a
lobster and then its mouth what is its
mouth even doing this whole part is soft
and it's full of food every animal that
dies and just drifts to the bottom of
the ocean these guys munch on that it's
honestly like God told Satan you can
design one creature he made this and
then he goes okay great but that can
only be on the bottom of the ocean
[Music]
shizzy is out the producer is out the
camera guys are out they tussled with
the ocean and lost I found a deck hand
to hold the camera and shizz's loss has
become Captain hasagawa's game as he
joins me for a Seaside Continental
brunch let's jump into it can you show
me how to do it all right so he takes
the head he kind of Hollows that out and
he cuts that away it looks like there
might be a bit of meat in there now
cutting away the rest of the hard top wa
we can eat that me wait only me but what
about both of
us I don't know what he's saying but I
understand what he's saying he's saying
hey you're the one who paid to go on
this trip I never wanted to eat isopods
okay I'm going to eat this one I'll do
it I'll do it uh so I'm going to just
grab the meat here we go
[Music]
o she it's a little sweet a little bit
of exhaust fumes and charcoal and then a
little bit of crabby kind of flavor and
I think we're good and I think you guys
feel good you feel resolution we went
out there we got the thing I ate it did
we capture the moment and enough one
more okay I'm going to eat one more I
made a rule a long time ago early on
when I was in the Philippines it said if
I can eat one of something I can eat two
of something it's weak to take a bite
and then just run when they have
Japanese TV Crews come out here they'll
actually take a bunch of these and go
stir fry them but I kind of like his
chimney smoke sming method more it's
kind of
[Music]
romantic are you going to eat with
me yes cheers
hi psycho psycho you got to be a psycho
to eat this but actually psycho means
excellent in Japanese from here do you
have any of that uh shark um extract I'm
going to see my girlfriend in a few days
and I want to make her happy
I'm a
[Music]
psycho oh my God shark oil should I
drink it or what do I do come drink all
right oh my God all right let's try it
out oh yeah I like fish
oil don't don't don't don't Zoom down
too much what we'll get demonetized
incredible experience thank you so much
you killed it I got the goas
[Music]
woo come
on you got get it isopods taught me more
than I could ever learn about them they
taught me that even if your goal is hard
I'm almost definitely going to puke
today look forward to that even if the
ocean is fighting against
you even if your crew will never speak
to you again yeah you're part of the
story now sometimes you need to push
past the pain in pursuit of something
bigger
[Music]
[Applause]
welcome back to our Japan series my name
is sunny and I'm shisuka and today we're
in Kobe what if it was that kind of the
show it makes you want to pom it a
little bit
right Japan has the highest value most
coveted beef around around the world and
coob is Japan's beef Capital first of
all this city is obsessed with beef when
you walk through and around the main
station there are more beef restaurants
than I've seen
anywhere It's Not Unusual to see cattle
selling at auction for 10 to1 15,000
ahead I'm just so curious with Kobe I
know there's the quality and the
genetics but how do you justify that
price in this video we're getting a rare
look behind the scenes going where few
Outsiders have gone
before anything touring a coob beef farm
and joining a live auction something in
something in something in revealing the
secrets behind how Japan has engineered
the best beef in the
world we got to turn Big Dreams into
action we got to mix action with the
passion time short no time for relaxing
be the first and last out make it
[Music]
thank you welcome to enco beef live
performance a place that lives up to its
name with veteran Tepanyaki chef and
owner Mr Kat takahiro at the helm
Tepanyaki is flat top Japanese cooking
right before your eyes with your very
own personal chef he starts off by
getting some vegetables going wow such
an appetizer
so that jumps around a lot this is
amazing it's like it's dinner and a show
at the same time first
[Music]
before things really start heating up
he's serving an appetizer a combination
of Kobe beef tongue orange mint
horseradish and green and purple
onion today we'll experience the finest
beef in the world coob wagu a steak this
big costs about
$250 according to the owner his
restaurant only purchases beef that
comes from local breeders and before we
dive into that marbled chunk of Heaven
we're going to see exactly how it got
here first of all thank you for having
us today yeah there to come meet Mr
nooshi his farm has been passed down
from generation to generation for the
last 80 years today he'll confirm or
dispel the rumors of Japanese Farmers
massaging cows playing them classical
music or feeding them beer all in an
effort to produce top quality beef we're
here because we want to know the secrets
about Japanese beef especially Kobe here
in in Kobe usually it's a secret but
just for you he's going to tell you
about it today and I won't tell anybody
secret secret
yeah you have a cute laugh Japan has
four famous domestic breeds of cattle
this is one of them the black Tajima
found exclusively in the hyogo
prefecture where coob city is located
does this cow have a name he calls him
Kudo which means black but usually it's
easier to be more specific by number
well 8443 it's been nice getting to know
you Farmers like natosi have no idea
what their cattle's meat will be rated
or how much money they'll bring in until
they go to auction so before that they
try to ensure optimal living and growing
conditions for each animal that means
fresh Mountain Air a reasonable amount
of living space at least compared to
American factory farms and high quality
food the main thing that he gives the
cows is essentially just hay and water
he gets the best from around the world
the highest quality hay from Australia
Canada in the US and that's what he
feeds these cows not just hay but three
times a day he feeds them a mixture of
corn soy scraps and other mixed greens
and ruffage in the US up to 75% of the
cattle's diet is made up of corn much
more than in coob if someone were to buy
a cow how much would that cost one cow
would cost about a million yen how do
you justify that price this breed is
actually decreasing in numbers so
there's higher demand but there's not as
many cows only about 3,000 cattle
qualify as coob quality each year
despite the intense demand for coob beef
around the world Farmers like natosi
still place an emphasis on quality over
quantity they have water misting
sometimes it's water but actually it's a
sake no like a sanitization liquid so
it's to keep them clean how often do
they get showered depends on the day but
about once every 5
minutes I'm just so curious because
there's all this mythical lore about
Kobe beef so what's real and what's
[__] [__] that's [__] right
there so do farmers really massage the
cattle the massage rumor is probably
false maybe if a TV company came maybe
they would do it could you pretend to
massage to them for our
video okay then do they play classical
music he actually tried doing that at
the beginning playing his own music that
he liked a little bit but then he just
stopped so what music did you try to
play that you liked is that a Green Day
Green Day wait see oh I can't even
believe this is real well then they must
at least be getting them buzzed on
Japanese beer he drinks the
beer the more likely reality is that
Japan's beef cattle have better genetics
and have been meticulously bred and
developed for hundreds of years they are
trying to protect the DNA they're known
for having a particularly pure bloodline
this is prize DNA that will never leave
this country unless it's in the form of
a
steak I think we should cheers so I mean
it's a special moment right now Cheers
Cheers come
by I love sake we have one more here I
think we should try out this is coob on
a leaf here we
go M very yummy mhm nothing too crazy
adding a little bit of Temptation yeah
it's the perfect appetizer but we're
ready for the real deal next we are
moments from biting into the ultimate A5
wagu beef that is world renowned I want
nothing more than to get this started
but I got to know what A5 even
[Music]
[Applause]
means this is a site few Outsiders have
been granted permission to see
you've heard of Farm to Table this is
the step in between hundreds of cattle
from various Farms across the hogo
prefecture soon the auction will begin
but beforehand each specimen is
carefully photographed and graded
there's no playing favorites here even
if you have the best breed and the best
intentions if your beef can't compete
it's going to get a lower grade what is
the temperature in here below 10° it's
pretty darn cold grading is done by the
Japan meat grading Association among all
these Tajima only some are graded A4 or
A5 qualifying as Bonafide coob beef this
stamp makes it official I saw a lady a
moment ago with a futuristic looking
machine and she was like taking pictures
here it is a camera and they're actually
just taking photos of the meat for
record purposes holy crap that's
intense in Japan the beef grades go from
B1 to A5 the higher the grade the better
the quality and taste the letter is in
relation to exactly how much meat is
actually on the cow how thick it is how
much meat is on there the number rating
is related to the marbling and the
actual quality of the meat besides yield
and marbling they also examine the
texture brightness and firmness of the
meat as a farmer what can I do to ensure
that my beef is always A5 is there
anything I can do this is probably one
of the difficult points even if you work
really hard as a farmer you still end up
with different grades of meat but in the
end it kind of depends on the personal
skill of the farmer this is why aashi
Farm where we went earlier today is
leading the industry with over 90% of
their cattle rated as official coob
beef after inspection the highest rated
beef receives the champion coob beef
award this prized beef kicks off the
bids for the day setting the stage for
what will be millions of dollars worth
of beef
sold Japan's usually a pretty quiet
place not right now there's a lot of
people in here a lot of
anticipation restaurant owners butcher
shops traders of meat all coming here to
place their bid right now they're
literally rolling in the
be the bidding has
[Music]
begun everyone's been looking at the
beef kind of taking notes on which
products they liked people are
electronically voting for which one they
[Music]
want all right they just made a
sale they bid on the price per kilogram
the highest bid gets the whole head of
cattle so this is 440 kog 3,800 Yen that
was
$115,000 for one cow that's
crazy after it's been auctioned the meat
takes a ride to a holding fridge until
it's brought to a restaurant cut
portioned and seared in front of two
very hungry
patrons let's do it the first thing he
does is give it a spritz of salt little
bit of pepp
the fat in KOB beef it melts very easily
and it can even melt in with just the
heat of your own mouth so in order to
make it just right they want to cook it
a little bit and then it'll be not too
oily for you oh he's going to light it
on fire what
ready oh my god oh man I felt that that
was really hot that was fascinating that
was amazing oh he's cutting it already o
there it is I'm going to put just a
little bit of salt on on it you got to
eat it while it's hot let's do it cheers
than what have I done to the discern
this
moment it is like kind of a tender fat
sponge almost each bite some delicious
juices just squeeze out it's touching
her heart in fact the oils are rushing
out to her heart but it's like heaven
too o
[Music]
squ I see him he's being transported to
another land trip to heaven right now he
might be prancing through some Fields
like a happy puppy you for and you're
back son of a [__] mhm that's
unreasonably delicious people who are
familiar with Wasabi they're maybe used
to having it with sushi but mixing it
with the beef it's something special it
elevates it it adds a different level to
it but beyond that that's like the real
Wasabi so it's coming like from the
Wasabi root and not the fake Sai paste
that's right I think a lot of people
look at the price and you can't think of
it like oh I could go to the store and
get a steak for cheaper it's totally
about the experience it's about being
here being in the city of coob having
your own personal chef who's cooked
thousands of cows in his life or
thousands of meals that's what I thought
you were going to say I think we could
totally enjoy the meal just so much more
just by watching the process of making
it and of course seeing his smile he has
such a lovely smile camera B do we have
the smile
[Music]
Kobe beef is a living breathing Legacy
symbolizing the meticulous unending
effort of Japanese Farmers over hundreds
of years when you drop $200 on a couple
hundred grams of beef in this city
you're not just taking a bite of the
best the world has to offer you're
taking a bite of History
cheers
awesome that was amazing I
those I'm just drunk at this
[Music]
point this trip has been amazing because
of Sunny I've been able to go to a whole
bunch of places that I've never visited
before yet in Japan I've tried many
foods that I've never had
before but also because of Sunny I've
had to touch bugs
no I've had to eat raw shark
heart oh you actually did it huh like
I'm not going to eat that and I've had
to endure 3 hours on the actual rockiest
boat of my life so today is about
Pap I'm trying to get into shizuka's
mind right now to figure out what she
could be planning for today I'm guessing
it's something uh cute enjoyable maybe
sweet like a multicolored cotton candy I
don't know it's going to be cute right
cute Kai Kai Kawaii today I'm making
Sunny eat wubo
[Music]
these are mud dwelling eels famous in
Suga terrifying to look at but even
better I'm going to make sunny catch
them first and he's going to have no
idea should be a pretty easy day I just
hope it's interesting for you guys so
let's see what she's got
planned today shizuka has brought me to
arak seat from April through October low
tide mean the sea turns into a huge mud
flat revealing all the amphibious
organisms as soon as I look in the water
I see it's teeming with life there's
little crabs there's mud skippers um are
we here for any of that actually no
we're fishing for something else today
it's a little different from a mud
skipper but I would say they're kind of
cute I knew you were going to make us do
something cute you know me so
[Applause]
[Music]
well our amphibia guide Mr Nakashima has
been in the fishing business for over 10
years with his experience and our
passion catching these creatures will be
a piece of Coke cake is it Coke or cake
hey is it Coke or cake Coke that doesn't
make sense who wrote this well hello
there thank you for having us today
today we are here at the mud flats doing
some epic fishing I'm told the animal
we're fishing for today is cute is that
right yeah yeah um some people would say
it's cute yeah it's cute yeah yeah um
are we guaranteed to catch some fish
today recently he's been catching quite
a lot of them so he thinks that we will
be able to that's good okay here we go 1
2 3 hey hey oh let's catch some fish
let's
go to catch a fish you must become a
fish starting with this unique surfing
board it allows me to spread my weight
out across a larger area preventing me
from sinking into the mud we're pumped
we're excited we're going to jump in the
ocean I mean the
mud let's go
oh [__] oh yeah unlike a regular
waterboard you don't use paddles you
don't use your hands you only need a
strong thrust from your leg region hey
it's pretty slick you're going the wrong
way
no
bye so we've come literally about 5 kmet
out here can you still see the
shore oh [__] you can all right we've
come very far out now what we're going
to look for some holes and then between
the holes we scoop okay so what about
here and here do those yes oh he just
got one oh I mean not yet but are you
making the Sashimi right now
brother why' you have to say the word
joke at the end of your translation are
my jokes not obviously
jokes okay jokes are hard to trans I'm
just telling you we just cut the mud
seven times now what well it won't
actually cut because it's not sharp but
this is the
movement in places like this the mud
gets a little bit harder to see so it
might be better better to split up oh
okay yes you're afraid I'm going to
steal all the
[Music]
fish okay guys I'm going off
board
oh oh no that was a mistake already
there's a hole here and there's a hole
here so maybe in the middle there's a
fish let's go for
it come on all right there's no fish
there did we bring any fish to like
throw in the mud and be like oh here's a
fish no that's what we usually do all
right I'm getting back on my boat oh why
did I get off my boat one would say that
based on my body type and my spirit
animal the mud would be my natural
habitat but life out here is harder than
I expected oh my boat's sinking I hope
it'll all be worth it when I meet these
cute fish shizuka can't stop talking
about Jizzy can I say I'm glad that I
let you choose the adventure this time
we're having a great time of course hold
on guys I got something what's
this what the hell is that that it's a
log it's not a
fish oh
sorry our four of mud fishing we're
having a lot of fun and we've caught
zero fish sorry I lost my temper
evidently there's fish somewhere in this
mud I don't know who put him there we're
trying to get him out it's pretty hard
even the guy who's an expert he looks
like he's giving up too but we can't
give up if we don't get any goddamn fish
we don't have an episode so we press on
he got yes oh my God yes he got one yes
he did it it's possible I never had a
shred of Doubt even he looks for Len and
lost right now oh I can't wait to see it
it did look kind of cute from here it's
long and it's a little muddy let's go
say
hi our effort is not fruitless he's
caught one I just saw it from afar it
did look kind of cute it's going to be
super cute I'm going to pull it out
right now as I look at this creature I
start to realize it's a
trap this isn't supposed to be a fun day
this I'm not going to eat that is a it's
moving around of my hand Revenge oh what
the that's not cute at
all you made me suffer on this trip you
deserved it this is a warasubo also
known as the aliens of aryak sea what's
up this eel like fish has been caught
and eaten by locals in the past these
days this gnarly creature serves as a
local mascot to promote tourism in the
area you know
I appreciate the tip about looking the
holes but hey they bite you that would
have been a good tip wow these things
are [__] vicious so you eat these uh
yeah some people in Saga prefecture do I
guess okay yeah not all people in Japan
no we got what we came for but just one
is not enough two eaters means we need
at least two
[Music]
warasubo oh [__] oh [__] you going one
oh oh [__] I
got it's trying to bite me you little
bastard oh I can't believe it there's
nothing like the rush of hunting down
your own food and providing for your
family or co-hosts it's Nature's cocaine
and I'm searching for another
line well guys I would love to stay here
all day up to my balls in mud but um I
think we got to go eat what we got can't
wait for her to get a taste and really
to just look it in the eyes may me give
it a kiss on the lips right chizy yeah
yeah totally
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah feel no pain I only gain red hot
blood running through my veins today the
creature which we will call food will be
prepared in a local pub named Toki isaka
run by Miss alal lagi toiko for the last
43 years her specialty drinking food
which is perfect cuz I'm going to need a
buzz to get this one
down hello there thank you for having us
today we just caught these water suo is
she proud yes for people in seab these
are friends yeah it bit me on the finger
[__] did it hurt
no even when you cook them they'll bite
you what these cute creatures
as shizuka calls them are normally
impaled through their head while they're
alive and hung to dry do you eat it like
this like some fish jerky the best one
is this and the second is in miso soup
the third best way to eat it is sashimi
and that's what we're here
for the preparation method of choice is
called E zukuri a Japanese word that
translates to prepared alive a method
used for some octopi fish shrimp and
today's unlucky warasubo so she starts
from the tail Works her way towards the
head the meat itself is super red like
blood red not enjoying this it grosses
you out I think it's not nice I'd rather
them just chop its head off a lot of
people would agree with you it's
actually outlawed in some countries like
Germany I think it should be but uh
Japan values the
freshness now she's told me to put this
on it I'm not sure what this does oh it
bit the spoon oh
shush
oh what this suck it it's sucky oh these
are little alcoholics there's no way
it's still alive it's definitely still
alive but that's just its nervous system
what does she think she's like yeah it's
still
alive are you going to try it I don't
know if I can try this one how about
these two heads boom cover it with a
lemon no no no that doesn't make a
difference it's just literally the skin
of the fish that you just shaved off
yeah I can't cover that that's the
actual food all right I'm going to try
it out let's
go M it's like a penis fish really it's
very chewy I like it the taste itself
it's not offputting it's not fishy but
honestly the outside skin is like Sandy
and coarse it's like grade one sandpaper
well little guys thank you for giving
your life that was pretty good actually
I'll try it again and that's only the
third best way aren't you excited that
there's still two more ways that are
even better yes so
[Music]
excited Miss Cho has offered us her
three favorite warasubo dishes and
shizuka has promised to try at least
one what a flipping day what an eventful
day damn I think the surprise couldn't
have gone better yeah here's my part of
the surprise there are three forms of
waru here which one are you willing to
try today as scary as this is I'm
curious to attempt that and even suck
the head suck that she told us she
should right we asked her she did I can
take a bite of the shoe my AP I think
that's s pretty good to me what I want
to show you before we work up to this
here so she said this is the favorite
and most popular dish of warasubo dried
grilled warasubo this dish is served in
sake but before that they have to
tenderize it with a hammer and Grill
them over an open fire for 20 seconds
cut them up and pop them in your sake
Appletini or Mimosa however you like it
all right let's try it
out it's so fishy wao usually I can't
tell much of a difference when I throw
something in in there I can tell yeah me
too it's bold it's daring it's alt-right
somehow too
altright this is like really changed the
experience and I can't say if it's worth
the better or not yeah it's I don't
really know why you would do this
normally I don't think anyone starts
with that I think when you're trash then
you're like let's start putting fish in
there yeah so I got a little fishy buzz
and now I'm ready to approach this show
my on Elm Street is not on the menu and
with good
reason our gracious host removes the
warasubo heads and steams
them then carefully removes the meat
mincing it along with soy sauce sugar
and sake you know what I would keep
telling you the cooking instructions but
I don't think anyone's following along
at home anyways so let's move
[Music]
on I'm going to go for this guy right
here very erect astute good posture wow
look at that
[Music]
it's pretty good it's pretty good mhm
you got to get rid of the head yeah it
seems the head may just be for show I
think it is oh I didn't even describe it
I don't know can you just tell them what
it tastes like it's like
salty I'm so bad at my show good good
effort good effort it's not bad at all
well prepared well seasoned and that is
full of the meat from tons of these
little guys yeah lastly I got a munch on
this head we got still a bit of fin here
the teeth are just bleached white at
this point oh
god oh it's
fun there not a lot of meat it's a lot
of hard stuff in fins no one does this
do they no but the L said you can um
suck on the yeah well you can suck on
anything technically doesn't mean you
should shizuka we've done it we rocked
it all right we did it boom Cheers
Cheers m
I've embes I've seen faces lifted
weights the revenge is a dish best
served cold how could you do this to me
but steamed is okay too Prett good it's
pretty good after raw shark heart
grasshoppers Japanese death boat and now
this I hope shizuka and I are finally
even no more cute creature hunting for
me luckily you can't tell that I just my
pants but next time you go to the mud
flats be sure you know What Lies Beneath
the surface
[Music]
today our cross country Japan Series has
built up to this Grand Finale
[Applause]
come in this port city of 1.5 million
shisuka and I will explore Japan's dying
food tradition when I heard street food
I thought it was going to be just Grill
and throw it on a plate but this is like
we're sitting in a proper five-star
restaurant look at this
presentation a tradition locals are
fighting for guys have you ever seen
such a nice diaphragm I've actually
never had diaphragm before but it may
only be a matter of time until the
government shuts them
down run fast and
the these are the most strict street
food stalls you'll find anywhere in the
world right behind me these guys are
setting up right now that's a crazy
amount of work just so I can sit on my
ass have some drinks and some damn good
food this isn't ordinary street food I
really got
this is yaai we have come to our first
yeai can you tell me a little bit about
this place this this is a family run
yeai business right originally the dad
started this business and then the
mother and the son are running into too
that's dope right here this very spot
this small chunk of sidewalk has been
theirs every night for the last 35 years
a not so ordinary Street stall with a
wide- ranging menu but tonight I have a
pork fetish and I'm into feet have you
ever had pix feet I've never had pix oh
man you're getting so many new
adventurous opportunities so many so
many I get it maybe because it looks
like a foot and I usually walk on the
ground with the feet Yes but the foot is
actually full of fat and collagen which
is good for your skin the skin yeah and
wrinkles this not so commonly used Pig
part is a favorite for those sipping
sake in
Japan the feet are brazed in a soy sauce
base for 5 hours then thrown on the
grill lightly seasoned and served simply
with shredded cabbage and vinegar soy
sauce we got some skin here that's just
pure gelatinous fat it's super tender it
is a little bit gy smelling Stone oh
okay it's much better than I thought the
texture really reminds me of like an
undercooked very soft chewy rice like
almost em Mochi rice it's a little bit
of animal liness but the thing with
drinking food is it's supposed to give
you a jolt of intensity so that you have
a reason to wash down your
beer true how you
doing true
[Music]
every night at dusk when the sun sets
over Fukuoka City on Street sides and
Alleyways these yaai come to
life but what does yaai mean to
Fukuoka meashi KIRO he owns aai called
No Cheto Rashi in uring he can bring the
best experience to his customers each
night starts here hello sir thank you
for having us today thank you higashi is
a newcomer to this traditional style of
dining only running his outdoor eery for
the last 2 and 1/2 years but his Isiah
the birthplace for most of his culinary
Creations has been around for 50 years
the word yti does it have a literal
meaning essentially what a yeai is it's
a
transportable food cart and for him what
they do is they bring their card out
onto the street and then at the end of
the day they pack up and they bring it
back to the
[Music]
restaurant I was in the USA recently and
I was talking to a lot of small
independent restaurant owners about
their restaurants and the regulation
they have to deal with and they are
finding it more and more difficult to
meet the demands that are put upon them
by different government agencies and I'm
curious as somebody who owns aai what
challenges do you face when it comes to
regulation in
Japan we have a very strict regulation
for size of the space the actual size
that you're allotted is 3 m x 5 m and
the size of your actual yeai shop should
be within 3 m and 2.5 M oh my God due to
regulations you can only start from 5:00
p.m. and then you have to leave by 4:00
a.m. and of course you can't leave
anything behind it needs to look exactly
as it did before of course right the
number of yatai have greatly reduced in
Japan as governing officials attempt to
clean up the streets but even some local
people see them as ior creating more
Ruckus than their worth for some who
stick to the old ways running a yatai
goes beyond a profession for them it's a
[Music]
performance here we are can we talk loud
in the confines of the yatai yeah we can
yeah we're Outdoors hakaru y Thai shop
has been around for 62 years having
passed through three generations a cozy
space that seats 10 at most but still
people line up for their turn at the
yaai table here as part of their menu
they served us up some of their Classics
we've got the guoa I'm going to split
these apart it's super crispy it's been
seared in a pen so you can see it's very
seared yoza dumplings filled with ground
meat and vegetables wrapped in a thin
dough here it's served with Yak kosha a
hot citrusy soy sauce wait you got to
dip it in the yak Koso it isn't complete
without
this
o m oh that is so crispy it's the holy
matrimony of deliciousness having its
wedding reception on my
tongue that's so nice it's a great
metaphor it's crispy on the bottom chewy
on the top and it's full of delicious
spiced Meats I love it m this is a great
y Tha food here sag it's translated as
diaphragm I've actually never had
diaphragm before Sagi is thin tender
skirt steak put it on a skewer toss it
on the grill sprinkle with salt and
pepper and it's ready for an intimate
night with your taste
buds oh yeah it's like medium rare
tender juicy the pepper really brings
out a nice flavor to the meat everything
here is just meant to be little bites
little tastes flavors textures to go in
between all the drinking so the more you
eat the more you want to drink the more
you drink the more you want to eat it's
a vicious cycle it could get out of
control pretty quickly it really can the
variety of your Thai food is Limitless
and the prices are more reasonable than
you might think $5 for ramen tofu soaked
in odang broth and beef tendon for just
a few bucks that's pretty good for some
tofu that's right I like it or this a
rare wild meat you don't often see
served in
restaurants meet head chef yoshito takah
well hello there Yoshi you working
together with Mr higashi they're winning
over locals and newcomers night after
night so right now he's deboning the
hind quarter of a deer where did you get
a deer
leg I'm dying to know what is the key to
outstanding yeai
service he says that a lot of people
feel a little nervous about going to
yeai in the city it's hard to kind of
like go and sit down next to someone you
don't know he believes it's his role to
help them feel at ease and enjoy the
experience that's incredible the part is
about to get started in 5 hours but
first oi oi psycho yes psycho py
psycho when I was a teenager at helping
my dad butcher deer I never thought of
actually eating the tenderloin
raw just take a quick look at this this
game meat it's so deep red like Scarlet
no fat in there this is a deer that's
been eating organic its whole life he
said they can't serve it to Guess that
way but I'm in the kitchen I've got
special access eat together yes all
right let's do it yes let's go I like
your enthusiasm for raw
meat it's like really
good that's a lot of meat no super
strong flavors at all nothing gy it's
just super clean salty like animal oil
in my mouth that's cool so every time
you're preparing as a Boss Fan know that
you just eat a
[Music]
couple right behind me these guys are
setting up right now and I do not envy
the work these guys go through each day
first of all the cart which fits an
incredible amount of stuff in there they
have the sink chairs pots pans burners
everything that fits inside now you can
see they've opened it up set it up
cleaned it up and then finally at the
end get the food out and then start
preparing the food that whole process
takes about an hour and a half something
I'm going to keep in mind next time I
see these on the street is all the work
that goes into it just so I can sit up
my ass have some drinks and some damn
good
[Applause]
food here we are after a long day seeing
how they prepar all this food the
results are here it is like five star
street
[Music]
food Yoshi does not take his food prep
lightly he's the captain of this ship
monitoring each guest around him making
sure they get whatever they need I
ordered a deer sausage I thought he
would just cut a hot dog into five
pieces throw it in a pole and give it to
me and then it's like a work of art
first a fried cheese roll then fried
sausage along with veggies artfully
plated Yoshi meticulously smearing
sauces plating each vegetable with
precision and then that cheese roll
bringing the dish to life and a fat deer
sausage popped on Top This is my first
venison by the way Bambi I wouldn't eat
Bambi by choice but here we
are oh that's really damn good that's
very juicy I would guess that they put
some pork in there
too steer meat is a little bit low on
oil and fat he's cooking it in pork fat
so the meat is still 100% % deer what
even is this that's some fancy ass
cheese oh I love that so good Fe
parmesan cheese that's wonderful high
quality beautiful to look at food is
Yoshi's strength like this deer steak
set upon a bed of flower petals it's
game meat but it's not game me at all
and wild boore meat too there's a lot of
different flavors in that one bite it's
the next level of yum it's not just
about the food or the booze although I
am a big fan of both can we get three
can you drink one I like
it it's about who you're here
with and who you might bump into along
the
way guys are we going to be showing up
huh
goodbye
yes right now I'm just a little bit past
9:00 p.m. they're just warming up in
Japan you can feel this switch turn
where people go from intense office jobs
expectations obligation and then they
flip the switch and forget about
everything else I think in Japan the
phrase Work Hard Play Hard really really
fits the bill yeah absolutely these days
yatai is a tradition only found in
Fukuoka a tradition whose time may be
limited but while it's here vendors all
around the city are going through the
backbreaking work of prepping food food
setting up shop and pouring drinks just
to break it all down that night leaving
no trace of what hangovers and laughs
were shared the night
before chizzy you killed it thank you so
much guys that is a rat on Japan I will
see you next time a
pe oh I'm going to get more alcohol
sleep I mean sleep and vitamins I want
to take vitamins I'm taking vitam
alcohol yes woo
ha